

KABIR FAISAL

PROFILE

I am a quality engineer and web-developer with a passion for building clean, stream-lined, responsive websites and apps. With a technical background in the various industry, including more than 10 years as a QA Engineer, I have an abundance of experience working with a diverse base of start-up, midsize corporate entities.

I have a history of solving problems and creating efficient solutions all while being both self-reliant and a member of a team. I recently received a certificate in Full-Stack Web Development from the Columbia | Engineering Boot Camp.

EDUCATION

2022-2023 Columbia Engineering Full Stack Software Developer Boot camp

2009-2014 B.S Computer and Information Security– John Jay College (CUNY)

CONTACT

PHONE: 646-651-8959

WEBSITE:

My Portfolio

<u>GitHub</u>

LinkedIn

EMAIL:

md.kabirfaisal@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

ACTIONIQ (SEQUOIA) NEW YORK, NEW YORK

QA Engineer Feb 2022- Present

- Execute Web API Testing using Postman and JSon languages
- Verify & validate documents and real-time data storage in AWS DynamoDB and MySQL
- Work on React.app code to add static unique property DOM attributes
- Developed functional (E2E and component) testing script using JavaScript with Cypress testing tool dependencies
- Developed API performance testing script using JavaScript with K6 testing tool dependencies
- Developed CLI script to run functional and performance testing in AWS s3 and from local command line
- Build CI/CD pipeline in GitHub action and/or Jenkins

Tools Used: TestRail, K6, VS Code, Cypress, Jira, AWS (DynamoDB, S3), MySQL

ZELIS HEALTHCARE, BEDMINSTER, NEW JERSEY

Lead Automation Engineer July 2019- Feb 2022 QA Automation Engineer June 2018 - June 2019 QA Engineer January 2018- June 2018

- Architected cutting-edge Selenium with C# based TDD and Data Driven automation framework solution from scratch for Window (Native Desktop) and Web application
- Architected Page Object pattern using Page Factory for readability and reusability
- Execute Selenium WebDriver Automation script with Visual Studio and C#
- Lead project of moderate scope and coordinate with various teams offshore and on-site to prepare test cases, data set-ups and test environments
- Manage script Build and release on TFS source control
- Verify & validate documents and data storage in MS Azure Cloud and MS SQL server R2
- Create Test Strategy Documents that define the test environment, testing process, and entrance/exit criteria
- Execute test cases/scenarios across development projects.
 Types of tests involve the application's functionality, user interface, regression, security, and user acceptance
- Prepare testing approach/plan and related testing activities using SpiraTest and TFS
- Monitor, drive, and report testing progress through test metrics; keep project stakeholders informed of test progress, issues and risks
- Execute Web API Testing using Postman and JSon languages
- Actively participated during implementation process of applications
- Ensure flow of go-live process by working alongside the project manager and team members
- Keep project stakeholders informed of test progress, issues, and risks

Tools Used: WinAppDriver, Selenium, Visual Studio, Appium, TFS, Jira

JASMINE UNIVERSE LLC, UNIONDALE, NEW YORK

Senior QA Engineer February 2016 - January 2018

- Manual testing and automating Jasmine's Mobile app & WinCE App and web platforms
- Analyzing FRDs, BRDs, mockups, and wireframes which followed with development of requirement-based test cases and artifacts
- Worked on Kanban methodology to test applications and ensure process flow up to release
- Updating existing application System Documentation and Users Guidebook
- Executing black-box, API and Database on prior to releases
- Build Automation Test from scratch for functional, regression tests using Selenium WebDriver with Visual Studio and C#
- Reporting defects and tracking tests using Team Foundation Server, Eylean
- Creating Test Strategy Documents that define the test environment, testing process, and entrance/exit criteria documents
- Executing complex SQL queries using MS SQL Server Management 2008 and 2014 R2 to verify and validate clientside input
- Leading QA team when necessary and implementing new ideas for the team
- Testing development environment, staging (QA environment) & production (Live environment)

Tools Used: Selenium, Visual Studio, Appium, TestLink, Eylean, TFS

FEDERAL HOME LOAN BANK OF NY, JERSEY CITY, NEW JERSEY

SQE II November 2014 - August 2015

BLUE CROSS BLUE SHIELD, FARGO, NORTH DAKOTA

QA Engineer September 2012 - November 2014

SANEF ITS TECHNOLOGIES AMERICA, INC., WESTBURY, NEW YORK

QA Tester May 2011 - August 2012